# M Usman Maqbool **Bhutta**

PHD CANDIDATE DEPARTMENT OF ELECTRONIC AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING, HKUST, HK

Robotics Institute, CYT Building, HKUST, Clear Water Bay, HK

□ (+852) 609-44-786 | wsmanmaqbool@outlook.com | wsmanmaqbool.github.io | @ UsmanMaqbool | msmanmaqbool | wsmanmaqbool | wsma

"Be so good they can't ignore you."

## **Summary**.

Apart from the research and coding, I'm good in the project management, networking for building teams, writing proposals and presenting ideas. I'm Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises. I've 5+ years of experience specializing in robotics R&D and project management. Current co-founder and COO of a startup which provides indoor navigation services using visible light communication technology [Lisee Technology Corporation Limited Hong Kong]. I have been a part of several other startups related to real estate, marketing, and automation. I'm a simple person who loves entrepreneurship and enjoys to develop the idea to reality.

## **Education**

#### The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology - HKUST

(Kowloon, Hong Kong)

PH.D. CANDIDATE, RAM-LAB, ROBOTICS INSTITUTE, DEPARTMENT OF ELECTRONIC & COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Sep. 2016 - Present

- PhD Supervisor: **Prof Ming Liu**, Director of Robotics and Multi-Perception Lab (**RAM-LAB**)
- Exchange Supervisor: Prof. Roland Siegwart, Director of Autonomous Systems Lab (ASL), ETH Zürich, Switzerland.
- Exchange Co-Supervisor: Dr. Cesar Dario Cadena Lerma, Senior Researcher at ASL, ETH Zürich, Switzerland.
- Got PEEF CCMS PhD scholarship from Pakistan and overseas research award (ORA).
- · Research: Multi-Agent SLAM System, Place Recognition, Autonomous Car and Deep Learning for automation industry.

#### Quaid-i-Azam University - QAU

Islamabad, Pakistan

M.PHIL. ELECTRONICS, DEPARTMENT OF ELECTRONICS

Mar. 2010 - Jun. 2012

- M.Phil. Supervisor: **Prof Hasan Mahmood**, Department of Electronics, QAU.
- · Research: Signal and Image Processing
- Grade: A

#### Quaid-i-Azam University - QAU

Islamabad, Pakistan

M.Sc. Electronics, Department of Electronics

Mar. 2010 - Jun. 2012

- 2nd position in batch
- Projects: completed 9+ projects related to C++, Verilog/HDL and Micro-controller programming.

#### Bahauddin Zakariva University - BZU

Multan, Pakistan

B.Sc. in Mathematics and Physics

Mar. 2010 - Jun. 2012

• Grade: 1st Division

## **Research Publications**

## Smart-Inspect: Micro Scale Localization and Classification of Smart Phone Glass Defects for Industrial Automation

Conference Paper

M Usman Maqbool Bhutta\*, Shoaib Aslam, Peng Yun, Jianhao JIAO, Ming Liu

of Information Matrix For Pose Graph SLAM

Oct 2020

IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS 2020)

Conference Paper

Multiple Lane Detection Algorithm Based on Optimised Dense Disparity Map Estimation
Han Ma, Yixin Ma, Jianhao Jiao, M Usman Maqbool Bhutta, Mohammud Junaid Bocus, Lujia Wang, Ming Liu, Rui Fan

Oct 2018

Accepted in IEEE International Conference on Imaging Systems and Techniques (IST 2018)

PCR-Pro: 3D Sparse and Different Scale Point Clouds Registration and Robust Estimation

Conference Paper

M USMAN MAQBOOL BHUTTA\*, MING LIU

Jul 2018

Presented in IEEE Int. Conf. on CYBER Technology in Automation, Control, and Intelligent Systems (IEEE-CYBER 2018), and won Best Student Paper Finalist Award.

BHUTTA, M USMAN MAQBOOL · RÉSUMÉ

JULY 12, 2020

1

### An intelligent approach for robust detection and recognition of multiple color and font styles automobiles license plates: A feature-based algorithm

Conference Paper

M USMAN MAQBOOL BHUTTA\*, HASAN MAHMOOD, AND HAROON MALIK

Published in IEEE International Conference on Audio, Language and Image Processing (ICALIP 2014).

**Efficient Reset Design Techniques** 

Jul 2014

2015

QAMAR, ZOHA, BUSHRA YASEEN, AND USMAN MAQBOOL

Published in Science International Lahore

Journal Paper

## Work Experience \_

#### INDUSTRY

#### **Lisee Technology Corporation Limited**

Central, HK

COO

Jan 2018 - Present

- Won funding support for company | TSSSU Support HK\$ 300,000 (Jun 19 May 20).
- Indoor Navigation for Libray using Lisee Technology | PCF Support HK\$ 160,000 (Jun 18 May 19).

#### **Friends Corporate Technologies**

Islamabad, PK Feb 2013 - Aug 2015

50+ Projects | Electronics/ Electrical Engineering, R&D, image processing, Web Applications Development, MVC Applications

**Federal Government of Pakistan** 

SCIENTIFIC OFFICER

Islamabad, PK May 2012 - Feb 2013

Electronics/ Electrical Engineering, R&D, image processing

Server4Sale, LLC

Islamabad, PK

PHP Developer Dec 2009 - Mar 2010

Php web application development for Joomla and Zend frameworks.

#### ACADEMIC

#### **Department of Computer Science**

BZU sub campus Sahiwal, PK

LECTURER (VISITING)

Feb 2016 - Jun 2016

Teaching MCS and BS-CS courses

#### **Department of Physics**

Government PG College Sahiwal, PK

CTI

Aug. 2015 - Apr. 2016

Teaching BS physics (Electronics related courses + Labs + Projects)

## Honors & Awards

#### INTERNATIONAL

July 2018	Best Student Paper Finalist Award, IEEE Int. Conf. on Cyber Technology in Automation, Control, and	Tianjin, China
	Intelligent Systems	rianjin, China
May, 2018	Best Proposal Audience Award, Campus Challenge - Transportation, HKUST	HKUST, HK
Nov, 2017	Best Mapper Award, Robotics and Multi-Perception Lab, HKUST	Shenzhen, China
May, 2017	Completion Award, The Graduate Teaching Assistant Training, HKUST	HKUST, HK
Dec, 2016	Best External Award, Robotics and Multi-Perception Lab, HKUST	Shenzhen, China
Nov, 2016	Completion Award, Author Workshop, Elsevier Publishing Campus	HKUST, HK

#### **DOMESTIC**

Sep 2016	<b>CCMS PhD Scholarship</b> , Won Chief Minister Marit Scholarship (CCMS) scholarship award by Punjab	Lahore, PK
3ep 2010	Government (PEEF), Pakistan for pursuing my PhD studies at HKUST, HK	Lanore, FR
Sep 2013	Participant, Painting for peace (Pakistan-India-Afghanistan) event, a part of the Harmony initiative	Islamabad, PK
Apr 2013	Participant, Case Spark in business plan competition	Islamabad, PK
Apr 2013	Participant, Case EPICA	Islamabad, PK
Apr 2013	Participant, How to be a Better Playwright Workshop by PNCA and US Embassay Pakistan	Islamabad, PK
Oct 2012	Participant, Punjab Youth Festival	Lahore, PK
Oct 2011	Participant, Int'l Youth Conference and Festival	Islamabad, PK
Sep 2011	Participant, Asian Youth Conference and Peace Festival	Lahore, PK
Apr 2011	<b>Completion Award,</b> Acting and Directing Theater Workshop by PNCA and US Embassay Pakistan	Islamabad, PK
Dec 2011	Participant, National Drama Festival	Islamabad, PK
Dec 2010	Instuctor of short Course, PHP Web Development' at the Department of Electronics, QAU	Islamabad, PK
Apr 2013	Completion Award, Running River Rafting course by Adventure Foundation of Pakistan	Mansehra, PK
Apr 2013	Completion Award, Paragliding course by QAU Adventure Club	Islamabad, PK
Dec 2008	Award of Honor, Finance Secretary of Electronics Student Society (ESS) at QAU	Islamabad, PK

## Academic Activities \_\_\_\_\_

IROS	Referee Service, IEEE/RSJ RA-L and International Conference on Robotics and Automation	2020
Spr 2020	<b>Teaching Assistant</b> , EESM 5547 - Multimedia Signal Processing	HKUST, HK
ICRA	Referee Service, IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Robotics and Automation	2020
Spr 2019	<b>Teaching Assistant</b> , EESM 5547 - Multimedia Signal Processing	HKUST, HK
CASE	Referee Service, IEEE International Conference on Automation Science and Engineering	2019
IROS	Referee Service, IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems	2019, 2018
Fall 2018	Teaching Assistant, ELEC4820 - Medical Imaging	HKUST, HK
Spr 2018	<b>Teaching Assistant</b> , EESM 5547 - Multimedia Signal Processing	HKUST, HK
Spr 2017	<b>Teaching Assistant</b> , ELEC 1010 - Electronic and Information Technology	HKUST, HK